hi David nice to reconnect with have we
not known each other like through iff I
think it was 2008 2009 around that time
when we first it's gonna be something
like 10 or 11 years I think I remember
meeting at Bioneers outside pioneers and
having a chat and that that must have
been 2009 but yeah nice nice connect and
um for a while now I've been just so
super busy that that I keep people tell
me about the collab and say wow
excellent David hojin had put put this
nice and collab on regenerating the
earth together and on the one hand I
feel bad that I haven't joined it yet
but I don't really know that much about
it but people speak highly of it can you
can you tell me a bit more about how it
came about and and what what the vision
for it is yeah like you okay came about
because like you Daniel and I like to
talk to lots of interesting people
working on regenerative and I'm
particularly interested in regenerative
activity so it ended up over the years
building out quite a network of folks
and I was finding that I spent I was
spending too much of my time just
talking to people and then making lots
of introductions to connect them
together and as a result and every time
I bump into that situation I'm like you
know is there an is there an easier is
there an easier way to to do this that
doesn't take up quite as much of my time
just sending emails so I I figured in
about September last year that I should
just try putting people together in a
slack Channel
actually was I I kind of started in June
of last year with a few people but then
you know across the summer and we
yeah very hard to get anything done in
the in the summer months just because
everybody's all over the place or last
year everybody was all over the place
I'm gonna save this year obviously and
so really I think of it starting
sometime around September and say yeah
we I just started inviting people along
to slack and running you know a variety
of zoom conversations group
conversations I just you know one or two
a week and just send out an invite hey
hey you know this pattern over time I
was doing it around specific members I
think and then I would you know play
around with various zoom facilitation
breakouts and whatever else to get
people into small group conversations I
was just playing around with different
facilitation formats and yeah people
people seem to really enjoy getting in a
meeting meeting one another and getting
to know one another and so over the last
six seven months I guess now yeah that's
that's got an appointment we've got
about 250 people you know from you know
technologists finance people people
running projects on the ground in
various different locations
Borneo Peru here in the US how do I have
to imagine like the actual those people
getting together you use theirs their
conversations going on in the slack on
the slack platform and then you have
student calls with everybody or how do
you get together it's very you know open
space so right now we're running about
five or six seven calls a week and you
know I've got a team of six five of us
one two seven seven of us who are kind
of taking this
ability for running different
conversations so we have a variety of
different conversations and it's very
much send a thing out and you know see
who shows up for a given thing and so
out of the 200 or so folks calls vary
between about you know small intimate
things with about three people a lot two
groups with twenty to thirty people and
we do we're kind of action oriented such
as this as some calls that are just
designed to mix people up but other ones
are very much focused on okay we've
identified this problem in in enabling
regeneration regenerative activity okay
let's get together and brainstorm things
that collectively could be done we could
do that would try and help solve that
problem and we kind of refer to those as
well
either co.labs or missions it's much
more and admissions so collab is much
more creative okay enough conversation
whereas a mission is much more of a okay
here's a thing let's get together and
see how we can move that thing forward
in the world i think like i spoke with
me not about this is not one of the
people helping you organize the yeah
least i'm not really well with equal
ease and other european networks using
zoom quite creatively to kind of
breakout rooms and also you know it's
really a servant to the movement and
many like also spanning across movements
which is great and i mean that's what
it's it's interesting I hadn't really
clicked that this is your response to
the the big conundrum that that Weaver's
like us tend to have that we're
constantly like trying to stay in touch
with such a broad network and wanting to
because there's nothing more joyful than
connecting to people that need to do
work together and can do stuff that no
one of them could do alone and but at
the same time it gets a bit tedious when
when you find that half of your week's
work or more is in
that and somehow there's more no
financial flux into supporting yeah it
can be tough time quite easily yeah no
it's crazy I looked at the website you
put together of the weekend looks looks
nice as a general sort of introduction
landing page and and that the
proposition that this whole network now
could be deployed to help people with
specific problems in specific places
that's the really the same central offer
is that right or you say but more about
that yeah it's nice and six Saints
Daniel yeah I mean that's basically the
the proposition because I mean what I
was what I was observing or at least I
was having so many conversations and so
many people and in every conversation in
every conversation you know people
running different types of projects you
know some software projects trying to
create platforms that support stuff or
on the ground projects and everybody you
know everybody always has needs
I've noticed you know nope I've never
yet I don't think I've yet found a
project that is entirely smooth sailing
right and half of it and that's where I
end up connecting people together it's
discussed oh you're trying to do that
and you're having a problem I know these
people you should talk to yeah so yeah I
need to get you as my copywriter Daniel
remember that there was you when I when
I had just published my book or maybe
even just before it came out
you mentioned because because it has the
word designing regenerative cultures
like the designing cultures in it you
said have you heard of this guy Joe brew
and I said maybe really and and and then
he put me in touch with Joe and and I
learned more about his work and now he's
like do you know have you been
with the process he just started is it
parallel complementary how is it how is
it different because I I it's another
one of those where I feel like cool cool
initiative nice people I'm sure focused
on the right mission the great work of
our times and you can't be on every zone
call it's good that we have that problem
now it wasn't the problem ten years ago
yeah Jojo I joined our you know I hadn't
talked to Joe in I guess last time I I
was talking to Joe about last year and
then we kind of reconnected again just a
few about a month ago actually so he's
now joined GRC and you know I just see
you know this is why the word collab is
in there right I just see all of these
things as being interrelate you know
it's a it's a network of people doing
initiatives and the more you can
interconnect that network at the end of
the day the you know you know pretty in
an action-oriented fashion the more good
stuff will happen if I could have an
entity that didn't have a name I'd
probably have an entity they could
another name because it's really about
all the great work but everybody else is
they're trying to move forward right
when we that the last times we spoke you
were also very active in the space of
trying to get people and together that
we're all trying to find new vehicles
for investment or bringing finance to
large landscape restoration like
large-scale ecosystems restoration and
regenerative activity in that space and
um is that somehow still linked with
that same
cool app initiative and and that's why I
was asking also about Joe because Joe
seems to be building some kind of
investment platform for regeneration and
I was wondering whether they are somehow
linked um so yeah you know finances is a
big big challenge within these things
and so we've got a whole bunch of
interesting in the way I yeah got a
whole bunch of interesting finance
people in the network who are working on
a whole body you know quite quite a wide
range of different initiatives to try to
figure out how to move more capital into
in an appropriate Roger in a
regenerative fashion right it isn't a
regenerative activity yeah cuz you know
the the standard relationship with
capital as we as we all know can be a
bit extract him so there's a need for
all sorts of transformation to occur to
set that up well so it's definitely one
of the core areas of inquiry and so yeah
in that context yeah Joe's current
initiative around this funds that he's
trying to set up nobody is in process of
setting up and focused well he was
talking about I mean he's in Colombia
currently but I'm not sure whether he's
thinking about it just to know fully in
the context of Colombia or more broadly
you know like it like most of these
early-stage ideas right it's in the
evolutionary process of you put a thing
out there start to get people talking
about it you engage people and then what
becomes possible you know you start to
see possibilities that you didn't see
before um so I think you he's somewhere
in that rapid developmental cycle right
now around oh yeah this question of
unlocking I mean both filling you know
philanthropic
and other types of capital to enable ya
regenerative activity especially the
convening piece right beep well at least
what are one of the key areas that I'm
about to try and unlock under the
community around is this question of how
do you support you know what's the right
business model how do you support this
Earl you know people who are bringing
together the regional networks in that
early stage before bears for generate
the projects and the opportunities where
you need blended finance come in but
that early stage is really hard to get
funded ripped yes but but it's it's so
interesting because like if you take for
example the the project that that I sort
of move you in with and that you
probably know in touch with more than I
am and the regenerating Network you know
that kind of initially was was basically
an idea that grew out of the
dissatisfaction with not being able to
give all the amazing runner-ups on the
last spring price some prizes because
they all deserved money to run their
amazing regenerative projects all over
the world both social and ecological
regeneration and that's when when back
then I first thought wait a minute the
same situation must be the case for the
Buckminster Fuller challenge I also
thought about the biomimicry design
challenge and a number of other em of
these beautiful kind of prize-winning
challenges but but then in talking with
with David Mocambo we we very quickly
got to this like could they be
redesigned in such a way that they're
not zero-sum games that they're not
about winners and losers and how would
you do that that that was my initial
kind of starting point for helping to to
launch that conversation and it's kind
of a both and while it still has this
vision of showcasing amazing
regenerative projects that have been
vetted through both the either the
spring prize or the buttons
for a challenge initially em showcasing
them to the world showcasing them to
each other showing that the movement is
much larger than we all thought is even
possible and also showcasing them to
anybody who wants to learn either from
those projects but also wants to support
them and um that part I really like but
then when we when we kind of started
talking more in the in the California
environment it very quickly brought in
these other types of impact investment
and other monies and I ever since then
it's just a feeling of mine that I felt
that that the initial power of this
project of really showcasing vetted on
the ground place sensitive place sourced
initiatives not initiatives that and
this is where well I wanna challenge you
just for a mutual learning this idea
that you can have 250 people who are all
committed mean well no shit lots of
stuff sort of come in as the expert team
to a specific location and a specific
problem that is really about that bio
cultural uniqueness of that bio region
in that particular place and that they
can generate a hell of a lot of really
useful stuff in a bunch of hackathons
online or even in place
it's probably a both and I'm not saying
that they wouldn't generate a lot of
really useful stuff but like big
question with it is if really arean
habit in place and redesigning the human
impact on place and planet from the
ground up core creatively is so much
about being placed sourced and sensitive
to the local ecosystem how big is the
role of the external expert in in that
do you see what I'm getting in yeah and
I mean I so I think it goes to your
other people use the word local too
right but I think it goes to this
concept of local where these you know a
regional thing you know right now most
of our attention is focused at this
macro or you know globalization right
and especially financial globalization
is this giant abstraction floating in
the clouds that is not embedded in place
at all and so it engages with place in a
way that is very incent is absolutely
insensitive to the to the bio you know
so all sorts of things locally
regionally and globally making you know
it's just detached from reality at a
certain level so I absolutely agree that
we you know the the the new pattern that
we're looking at is strongly placed
based is strongly placed sourced was
that the phrase use something and where
it is people in them you know a network
a community of people in that place with
or time with self-determination going
here's what needs to be you know here's
what we think
as the inhabitants of this place is the
right thing to be doing it will still be
embedded in some kind of
yeah it's we did each one of those nodes
and activity places nodes of activity
each one of those places is still part
of a larger system going to be prop a
larger system at least is if my is what
I would posit I don't think we want to
entirely have those things divorced from
having any kind of interconnectivity
really completing what you know what and
what I would say is that and often in
some of those places that kind of those
there are pockets of expertise that
aren't necessarily present in many of
those places that allow you know whether
it's a certain kind of yeah this is
where I find that that this logically
this makes perfect sense to me and this
is where I find the distinction
sometimes with people who I like in the
visioning stage if we want to bring us
bring a local network together and work
with this entire region to become
regenerative and we've got a really cool
team of people that are very committed
and we're gonna make this the region
region yeah and it's great and that what
I just feel like from my experience of
having seen this first move out from the
little nucleus that was the finding on
eco village and trying to work with the
Moorish iron region more and in undo
some of that bubble effect that happens
when when the Eco village was was first
formed and really start it was actually
called the building bridges program and
working with the local communities and
the local government and so on like I
brought when I worked for friend on
college it was the regional government
that funded my job and that was a kind
of precedent for how the community
started to work with the regional
funding bodies in the same here on
Majorca like coming down starting with
education doing a Eco village design
education program in 2011 that really
build community here um but then the
crisis that started in 2008 it really
hit Spain in 2011 12 badly and
and and so that kind of fidget that
initial community a little bit but lots
of really cool project started and so on
but what I'm getting it is I've been
slowly trying to do this work and when
it gets down through the real cultural
identity of a place then just for my
personal experience and that's when sort
of responding from and things like like
I remember when somebody told me in two
years into being on my yogurt and
Majorca told me don't be quite so
visionary this can all be done and let's
do it now and waiting your arms around
because it just doesn't matter with the
local culture very well yeah you you
just stick you laid too much I still do
that and and any and you also said to me
don't burn out because I would love your
impulses to to be to ground on this
island but you have to actually think of
it but most of the people here if you
still here in ten years time they will
start to listen to you and what you do
in between is just as important that you
don't burn out in the process then that
you do a few things that establish you
as somebody who's committed to wanting
to contribute and serve a larger whole
and that was best piece of advice I ever
got her um in terms of working locally
and so I don't walk around and spout big
sort of I am regenerating my Orca blah
blah blah because it's a very slow
process huh it's it's a and and the more
you communicate it the more danger you
actually create of it backfiring on you
because you actually would be nurturing
and doing social acupuncture and weaving
connections and like for example that
the stuff that I did with with eco we're
bringing eco veil on Majorca to
experiment with a regional biomaterials
economy yeah and we never went into mass
production of floor cleaner or hand soap
or any of the products we were playing
around with but we pulled together a
network of people from the University in
Barcelona that was testing biomaterials
that we sent them from Majorca
the local chemical that the guy who had
previously imported chemicals and mixed
them together to make eco detergents on
the island was looking at how can I find
these resources more locally and another
guy who had a perfumery was bringing in
local cents from lemon and rosemary and
in in the process because they all saw
their piece in a very systemic design
puzzle that was actually looking at
cascading resources through the
biomaterials economy and closing loops
and all those kind of things even using
satellite data to in real-time look at
what's growing on my Yorker to know what
the harvest will be to know what a waste
you will have well we never got to it
all of it in Rio but by talking about it
and bringing everybody together on a
real project it trained people to think
in that way and that has had ripple
effect so there's a lot more people now
thinking in circular economy and
biomaterials terms than they were before
and I'm just telling this story as an
example of how we also ran with forum
for the future some sort of event where
a bunch of expert consultants from
foreign for the future were here and the
head guy from innovation from eco where
was here and it generated a buzz and a
reason to meet but those are the things
that really regenerate a region these
kind of bringing in the expert teams in
in my experience they just said impulses
no I don't disagree with anything you
just said
so the yeah I mean that it's it's more
about the cross I mean I think about it
more in the terms of cross-pollination
especially amongst the
it was a really nice way of naming your
activity because you are like butterfly
because yeah I mean and and that work of
exactly what you're describing I mean
that's an excellent Lu sedation because
the right word sorry that's two two
patients right it's simpler words
something of the process that you know
hopefully it is unfolding in many
different locations where there are
people who attempt you know who are
doing exactly the work you just
described right in that place of and I
was talking to a friend of mine who's up
in she's up at the University of Oregon
I think it was up in Oregon and she's
been doing similar convening they're
bringing together you know bringing
together the old you know members of the
old logging families that are there
along with you know city representatives
along with whatever else to start you
know within some kind of framing around
let's just start to step back a little
bit and look at this place we are in a
different way and start to have these
conversations about the future and what
could be possible and you know Nate I
think Kate gray worth came in and did a
doughnut economics lab as part of that
mmm
process and you know that's good it gets
a it just provides some extra inputs
into the place-based creative process I
mean that it's not about you know doing
exactly the thing and going these
experts will tell you what to do but
they they do you know it's like having
you come in and give a keynote speech or
whatever it is somewhere it has a lot of
battle you because suddenly people go
well that's an interesting way of
thinking I've not thought about things
and quite that way before
and it just
in Richard you know think the goal is to
enrich the creative conversation so but
thing you know people start to just go
oh that's interesting it's not about but
we'll know what to do right it's hey
let's think about these things in a
creative way together and you just see
where we get to I like it so much better
that way and like communicated that way
because there's always this slight and
it sorry I mean you're not American but
you live in America but it's this
American oversell of would bring the
expert together and like even you the
framing like I as much as I feel that
regeneration is bigger and broader and
more diverse than only the valuable and
important lineage of Carroll Sanford and
Regenesis but but in honoring as some of
that lineage like the simple approach of
and starting from we have a team you
have a problem we find solutions and one
of the kind of phrases central to that
way of working regenerative is you start
from potential and you don't stop from
problems and but they I I like in what
unit describing and rather than kind of
expert team comes and solves your
problem but more expert team comes and
gives you more multi perspectival from
multiple intelligences and multiple
expert disciplines perspective on your
situation and asks you questions like I
mean that's why in the end as vague as
some people get frustrated they're
designing regenerative cultures and then
I constantly just ask questions rather
than say I have an answer and they kind
of go somewhere else because they were
answers but but I find that answers are
bit arrogant like em it's the answer
lies in the process of questioning
together and that's what you would just
describe it and I think that's more
humble its more participatory it's more
engaging
I love I love like cape
and I and Anora and a group of people
were talking about taking what she's
developed with Portland and brought
Pittsburgh and with Amsterdam which my
Amsterdam has taken on just recently it
was in the body and how are they in our
doughnut City and so on and but I love
that process that she call developed
with Janine Benyus
the thriving places methodology and she
we were sort of hat does not happen with
with with Cove it and all that we were
exploring bringing a group of people to
Majorca to play with me or confer a
number of days on a using these like the
doughnut and the citrus and different
methodologies but bringing in Stuart
Cohen from from cattle Institute in
regenerative communities network and and
my kind of like iff three horizons
toolkit and all that and and expand a
little bit from what currently but this
thriving places methodology is looking
at cities and as we both like to work by
regionally but that was my only when
when Katie suggested like what what what
can we do differently I said well the
way to work with cities is to work with
it within the regional context so it's
really and and yes
it would have been exactly the same
theme of some experts internationally
reknowned like weaving wrong data to
make people on Majorca bring all of
their knowledge about Majorca in in a
kind of trance contextual data way into
the room and yeah so far so far it's
just a dream but it's developing I think
these processes are super important so
how do people engage with : if somebody
wants to join it can everybody join or
you write an application or how does it
go this thing it's a good question
so one of one of the things that over
the years I've tried running these
things is that I've noticed that
things work better I mean you want a you
want the diversity of you want this
broad diversity of creative perspectives
as possible because that's what leads to
creative possibility but you know one
one one needs to avoid too too much
dogmatism
and and certain kinds of negative
behaviors so it is a you know we have a
we have a boundary around the thing it
is a currently it's primarily through
referral ish and you know there is a
contact form on the website and you know
we we we you know if people reach out
and are interested I'm you know what
we're more than happy to jump on a call
and have it have a chat with whoever
which one but you know we're a bit
bandwidth constrained so they make it
may take a while to get back to you you
know I'm not going to guarantee a 24
hour response time and the geeks the
goal is yeah the goal isn't necessary to
grow a really large community right
that's not like the where where we're
heading
it's about people who can play play well
together to help yeah cult the cultivate
the conditions for this a regenerated
future to emerge but yeah I mean if
people are interested in being part of
this then just send us a you know send
us something through the contact form on
the website and we'll have a chat yeah
and cuz you know the I wouldn't say
randomness but what what I've discovered
over the last few years is very high
levels of serendipity occurring right
and
the people the people who are likely to
listen it's going to be very interesting
people at least from my perspective
otherwise if they're still listening
after what it is right now I don't know
forty minutes
what people don't have a more than five
minutes attention span on on YouTube so
particularly about rap to people
rambling on about how to save the world
more effectively in the ourselves and
nobody but I really appreciate that
you've pulled that together because it
is like there are all just opportunities
it's the same like I see it
like Joe's kind of working group around
the book that he's writing it's it's
precisely what in this kind of non
descriptive way when I was saying like
throughout designing regenerative
cultures runs this theme almost when I
read it as I think maybe I've overdone
it a bit because I come back and over
and over again to this living the
questions together having started with
the the real key quote on you have to
live the questions and sometimes you
can't be given the answers you actually
have to live into them and and I believe
that that's exactly what these things
are they and they have this global
tension of how do we like there's a
number of tensions just from again from
my limited perspectives that I've I've
identified that one tension for me is
how much energy to put really locally
and regionally into the deep
relationship weaving that isn't just
with the usual suspect but it's really
much more in a kind of you lab and
all-inclusive thought process bringing
in like the tourism industry the the
local whatever be a delivery company the
local sewage treatment plant all all
that reality and and the connected lives
behind that the people who want a job
and just want to feed their children and
and and have a relatively like don't
want to take responsibility for
the future of Majorca because that is
reality as well and and so for me um
it's really important to engage more
with that but I feel that will take me
away from having conversations like the
one we're just having right now and and
like I've had long conversations with
steward about this of the role of the
regenerative communities Network in
helping all these different regional
initiatives to learn from each other and
with each other in the right balance
between that learning and exchange and
open innovation and maybe even support
in in different ways and giving them the
time to actually do the work locally so
they don't disappear in the networking
in the reporting back to the global
community about something that is going
terribly slow because nobody is putting
attention there um and for me it's
always been a bit of attention to
working locally it's it's like in iff
and three horizons h3 you need terms
it's dilemma navigation like in in the
second horizon space we're constantly
doing the ulema navigation between stuff
that I is kind of Hospice in the dying
system and stuff that is Midwife in the
new system and and and that's actually
necessary to my mind yeah well now I
mean cause back to the the bridge thing
right it is as yeah
but somebody there is that dynamic about
tension you just described yeah just
describe to well then the year that
there is a need and not everybody
bridges you know yeah there is hyper I
believe at least there is high value in
that particular bridging function from
the group of local bridging function
because it does it allows you know it's
like a cell right you know again you
know that berries and nutrient flows
through the cell boundary to the cell
wall if the if that wasn't there or if
the you know that that boundary needs to
exist because you need to otherwise
there is no cell there and you don't
want to be in a a you know and you put a
cell in a saline solution or some kind
of gradient right and it just sucks all
of the the water out of the cell and
kills the thing so you don't want too
much outward flow and you don't want
huge inward flow because anything which
just blows up so it is how do you get
yourself give that thing the appropriate
boundary where you've got the right flow
of nutrients that makes the system as a
whole flourish free and so there is and
it's different if you know and it's
constantly shifting what you need now
and what you mean tomorrow and what you
need the next day and how you balance
those things out it's a dynamic it's an
ongoing dance that we have to be
continually just going what's the right
thing you know what's the balance right
now and whatever reason I've taken on I
like I like your mother's was made they
both do get organismic metaphor and the
dancing metaphor that's it's so ya know
actually as you were describing it I had
this idea for I even wrote it down here
could be a poem could be it could be an
essay and the O's
take balance of glocal it is like how
much can do you get sucked out of the
system money
ya know is bad but that's for me like
it's it's actually speaking to something
that they are saying that there's a
couple of pitfalls there's the the
pitfall or the the dilemma between the
glocal dynamic em then there's a dilemma
to my mind that the minute you bring in
even well-meaning financier types into
these kind of situations like even like
for example you're super successful with
with the collab and suddenly you some
some really big money says yeah cool
will will underwrite you and will bring
in all this money and you just go into
lo all these locations around the globe
and we're bootstrap and and blah blah
blah yeah but but there's plenty of
people like that in in the Bay Area you
know that and em and then you because
you're also bringing money you skew
quite a lot of the relationships to when
you come into a local process huh you're
not just the expert the global experts
that are flying in you're also bringing
money and and so people are rolling over
and playing along a bit because because
of that and and and that's also possibly
dangerous and so there's always a
there's really like how do we enable
finance to flow into regenerative
projects like then very close to that is
the whole although get people working on
on holo and and other kind of tokens
Bitcoin enough Bitcoin but but
blockchain based yeah yeah I deeply
believe and I know some of the people in
those spaces that they did completely
committed and doing doing wanting to do
good work and wanting to serve and then
there's this whole kind of are we
enabling are we building infrastructures
that will somehow enable a enclosure of
em
different types of capital that are
currently actually still outside of the
economy like real social capital and
real natural capital the minute we
monetize it and even though if it's
through some kind of other mechanism it
becomes really dangerous because then
you can what it can get one-to-one
translation into real currencies and and
suddenly you you meant to do well and
bring this into a more balanced more
holistic economic accounting but in the
process you actually created the monster
that enables the monetization of human
relationships and bio productivity and
that's also a bit of a dilemma because
on the one hand it serves and on the
other hand it doesn't the whole
technology thing is always a dilemma
like like how super tech does a
regenerative future have to be and and
if it is so super like that's what I've
realized a lot with this whole kind of
corporate thing in and people getting
into like even people who I would have
thought a wiser saying oh yeah let's
just all be monitored by our smartphones
and have chinese-style control yeah and
I just don't get that that people really
believe that a that's a desirable future
be there's a colonialism in that because
there are lots of cultures that don't
actually want to use smartphones all the
time that don't want to have their lives
ruled by a bunch of tokens that are
zeros and ones in a virtual space
they're choosing to live the human
experience and the human-like being
human in different sets of relationships
and if we want to be a regenerative we
need to create a diverse space where
those people have equal rights to stand
in the world and be active and have
rights in the world without having to
have a mobile phone-based system and
being plugged into the this the virtual
world for me that's a big shadow that
we're not talking about when we were
bringing
regenitive solutions into into the world
and living in the Bay Area and having a
tech backdrop and what do you think of
that I know it's fascinating the what I
think that I mean my eye I yeah inquiry
because you get an easy easy way out
card you can just say it's analemma I
totally agree with every word you just
said
I know but I mean I yeah at some level
there is you know there various value in
these things there is value in
technology there is value in finance
their tools the way humans have created
an amazing look at people smart people
with a good heart really wanting us in
those words I'm not
yeah right and the pitfall and there are
dangers to all of them well yeah I mean
the BBB the history of technological
colonization and how that yeah I mean
there is and the history of financial
colonization is quite ridiculously large
right and yeah how so and the nature of
being human where we need well within an
economic well and it can be argued that
there there are only you know economics
human humans have been embedded in
economic systems
and have been creating incent you know
inadvertently creating incentive
mechanisms
since we're you know since we were
pretty human and some level when we see
economic behaviors within animals right
it's not just a human thing we just now
have created or at least of the last
what three thousand years have had these
things that we refer to as money that we
allow but allow us to exchange these
totally abstract things between
ourselves an account and you know and
create accounting systems and whatever
else that allow our economies to work in
a in a different way you know I could
say that in a higher way but I'm not has
some kind of implicit value judgment and
I'm not sure that should be there so if
we have these kinds of incentive
incentives at the end of the day comes
down to human consciousness right of how
humans interact with these economic
systems that have emerged around us we
can't and all the digital tools are that
we're creating and these other financial
structures are just in half more refined
ways of thinking about how economic
activity in the natural world
interrelate that become some of which
becomes possible because of digital
technologies or at least the accounting
part of that but yeah you know embedding
human nature within those macro
accounting systems will lead to perverse
behaviors which won't and yeah which
will lead to the kind of you know people
going oh yeah we must do this natural
accounting system with this digital
technology here because that's one of
the big fallacies that I hear over and
over again that people say just because
you design and I'm all for designing as
nature
M or doing biomimetic design and how
many weapons systems have been designed
with biomimetic examples and how I mean
so basically you can turn I mean all
technologies like that can be turned to
good or to evil and and for me that the
way that we like for example just today
I had a conversation on social media
with somebody about the whole like the
Venus Project and Jack Fresno's vision
of the world and I don't really want to
live in a world where some kind of hyper
AI is measuring all forms of resources
and all my activities and and I kind of
run bound a multiple scorecard of things
up and down and up and down but I have
an equal share but I'm completely
basically plugged into the system and it
sort of assumes that there is a kind of
benevolent of the scientists it is
always in fresnels kind of oh yeah
that's good there are after worry it's
the scientists they're clever people
it's simplistic isn't and by which
scientists and and but but in a similar
way of noticed this like in your my yoga
I've had conversation with people around
a campfire or in other settings where I
thought this is my I'm with my people
they're talking about supporting local
farmers and and building a local economy
and and reconnecting with the story of
place and and the ancient myths of
Majorca and and keeping them alive in
the modern world and all of that sounds
nice yeah and then suddenly you realize
they're in that circles actually in a
sort of right-wing return to the local
building lifeboats in a difficult world
keeping the foreigners out and I mean it
did their subtlety and the very small
yeah but but what I'm saying is that in
the bioregional in
pulse we also have to be aware that
there is an underbelly of that
realization in there if it's not done
globally with global solidarity and
global open knowledge exchange and
support to both heal place and planet
then it very quickly can become of oh no
we're just trying to get it right for us
we're just a bunch of like made a bunch
of big movies in Hollywood and now I'm
gonna buy half a valley in Argentina and
and bring all my mates and have the best
regenerative designers create a kind of
tourist Lodge that some people can pay
me rent in to come and live in my
lifeboat and kind of vision I mean
that's that's movie not right-wing
that's just just ultra capitalist the
vision of my regionalism but there are
these other models that they're actually
not really am truly regenerative from
[Music]
otherwise like if we if we talk much
much longer than we'll definitely be
like we're almost getting into the
danger zone of you know Bucky gave these
talks where he would start in front of a
big audience and some university
somewhere and then about 90 to 120
minutes into it when the first people
had actually plugged up the courage of
saying this guy isn't gonna stop I'm
leaving and then you would sort of look
around and say say people well now the
people are supposed to be still here and
we can get started and any gone for
another time I think that might have
worked in the sixties I don't think it
does anymore we trained our attention
spans three for three
anyway really nice to reconnect and I'll
put I put this out on the regeneration
rising whatever it is set of videos that
I'm putting out on YouTube
and and I'll put the the website is
followed here somewhere where was it GRC
dot earth ah same you mentioned that
folks from common Arthur in that you do
you mean like through Sen Stuart is in
it was Freya or anybody also in the
collab Fred Friendster nice yeah first I
love talking to friends I mean that's
the beauty that is actually a really
nice global community and there's sort
of nuances of difference of how but
that's great that's our diversity that's
like as long as we keep engaging and and
and honoring multiple ways of seeing
things it's it's just gonna add strength
and diversity to the network but it's
difficult times like who knows where all
of this is going on I'm still like for
me I'm still in that mode where I don't
really want to make many comments about
Corbett nineteen changing the world
because it's still right in the middle
of it and we'll see where we end up I
have taken your part of the world yeah
Spanish couple are the ones who be
talking about universal basic income
right now I mean the right briefly to
talk to you earlier about this the
potential where I live now like on the
one hand all my work that was starting
to try to position some of the openings
in people in the tourism industry to a
new way of working with things and say
okay you still you're making lots of
money with this tourism you can invest
it in regionalization and building the
infrastructure we will need in five to
ten years to weather climate change and
all the other changes well that's just
gone out of the window and so like I
think tourism isn't gonna recover not
even in the next three or four years if
it recovers if
the system that it sits in recovers
which is also still a big if but but
yeah eighty percent dependency on
tourism so I live in a completely like I
mean basically the island is in ruins
with regard to its economy and that
collapse of course could be terrific but
it could also be a terrific opportunity
and so we'll see oh yeah but the first
use of the word terrific they're
actually more around the original
meaning of terror yeah terrific in the
sense of oh my god what has just
happened what's happening here right I
mean lots of really really scared and
and and also finding the balance because
you can't really when people are kind of
shocked into a survival mode kind of red
V mean cluster type Sparrow then a
McLean and to come them with with high
goals for Humanity is it's just like
there's a quick occasional disconnect
there so it's how to build with
everybody out of this mess a future that
isn't making the mistake of trying to
rebuild what we had before because that
was just running on fumes and about to
collapse anyway so interesting times
Graham's book I mean it was great I know
Graham had a hand in right here powerful
times a man Kelly's know yeah I should
sitting at my bookshelf downstairs I
feel like I should actually I like the
short little books that game and marine
and like the IFF has put out a number of
really nice short little books that my
inspirational anyway I probably should
take my daughter to bed and and spend
some time playing with her before yes
yes really really nice to see you again
and let's stay in touch there
okay